# **Greg DiPietro**

Front End Developer / Pittsburgh, PA

#### **A BOUT**

A problem solver and critical thinker that has the users' interest first. My expertise in front end development and interaction design pair with a wide array of technical and communication skills. I've been building and honing my craft for over 10 years.

Phone: (724) 689-2427 Email: <a href="mailto:gjdipietro@gmail.com">gjdipietro@gmail.com</a>

# **Core Competencies**

- Responsive, mobile first, front end development
- User experience and interaction design
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### Front End Developer

Guru.com, Pittsburgh, PA / May 2013 to Present

- Implement new features from concept through release
- Manage and maintain user controls and user interfaces
- Maintain all CSS throughout the application (SMACSS methodology)
- Develop reusable Sass modules and layouts
- Led research, design, and development of a consistent look and feel to create more usable and engaging product
- Support application through bug fixes

#### Web Developer

Schramm Farms & Orchards (freelance), May 2013 to Present

- Researched and analyzed client's business and assessed requirements of the new system
- Conceptualized, designed and developed custom WordPress implementation
- Executed a, mobile first, responsive design

#### **User Interaction Engineer**

Guru.com, Pittsburgh, PA / Sep 2009 to Sep 2013

 Collaborated with development team and marketing team in refining design, layout, and functionality of the product

- Developed interactive prototypes of all new features in HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- Evaluated usability and practicality of all designs

# **Usability Analyst**

Guru.com, Pittsburgh, PA / May 2007 to Sep 2012

- Responsible for creation of business requirements document
- Identified and prioritized user needs throughout the product
- Provided technical support to end users

#### **ABILITIES**

(C): Competent / (P): Proficient / (E): Expert

Front End	Tooling
Semantic HTML markup (E)	Grunt (P)
CSS3 via Sass & Compass (E)	git (P)
JavaScript (jQuery, AngularJS) (P)	TFS (P)
Templating (AngularJS, Mustache) (P)	Command Line (C)

Design	Back End	Development

Interface Design (E) Firebase (P)

User Interaction (E) .Net (C)

Site Planning (E) PHP (C)

Graphic Design (Logos, Assets) (C) MAMP (C)

Typography (C)

#### **Software**

SublimeText (E)

Adobe Fireworks (P)

Visual Studio (P)

Github (P)

# **EDUCATION** Bachelor of Information Science

University of Pittsburgh / Sep 2003 to May 2007

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- Elected by faculty as Class Marshall

# CONFERENCES

- Web Design Day 2012 & 2013
- Build Right Workshop presented by SparkBox
- UXPittsburgh Meetup
- Refresh Pittsburgh